when you're a new nrad I don't know it's
just you don't expect to see like
venuses at work or any nudity at work
eaing all these cool things whatever and
I leave all of that to realized I don't
know a damn thing today's conversation
is with Evan King he's a software
engineer who grew to staff by the age of
25 he had a lot of things to share when
it came to Growing your career quickly
we also thought it'd be interesting to
interview both ways because his career
growth matches mine very closely and so
for each leg of the career not only does
he go over what he learned but also I
provide context on my as well I hope
this conversation is helpful let's get
into it today's interview is going to be
a little bit different from the ones
that I normally do we have Evan on the
podcast I actually don't know of anyone
who's got promoted to staff faster than
Evan absolute rocket ship trajectory got
to meta and got promoted to staff in
three years which just means he got to
promo every single year so he has a lot
to to say I'm really looking for the
conversation and one thing that we're
going to do today that is different from
a normal podcast is because his
trajectory is similar to mine as well we
both grew very quickly very lucky in in
our trajectories we will do kind of a
back and forth where every time Evan
answers I'll also kind of give my
perspective on how it was for me yeah
totally I'm really looking forward to
this round this is going to be a lot of
fun and I'm especially excited to hear
about your journey because that's
something that even offline you and I
haven't chatted about yet so yeah yeah
absolutely and I think there's some
stuff in here I've haven't set anywhere
before so we can uh see where it goes
nice that'll be exciting so okay let's
let's get in the first thing first thing
is like the beginnings of your career
even before you got into the industry
when we put out that content showing how
quickly you grew there was conversation
about are you this brilliant person
who's been coding since you were 5 years
old or were you someone who started
studying at a normal time so I'm kind of
curious how did you get into studying
computer science I had computer science
offered in my High School AP Computer
Science which compared to most this is
certainly early but it I felt late like
most of the people in that AP Computer
Science class I grew up in the Seattle
area around the Seattle area most people
in that class had a dad or a mom that
worked at Microsoft and so they had all
been programming since they were super
super young and I was horrible like I
knew nothing and it was incredibly
complex and I was like I was so down on
myself and up until that point i' had
been a straight A student um so it
really stressed me out it made me feel
like this wasn't something that actually
clicked for me but you know I was
resilient enough to make sure that I
didn't lose that a streak and worked
really hard in order to do well enough
in that in that course
but then when we got to college I didn't
think I was going to do computer science
I just joined the engineering school and
you have an intro to computer science
class and because I had more of a
background than the majority of others
who had no CS background now all of a
sudden I was good and better than other
people and it's like that human nature
that when you're good at something it's
exciting and and you want to keep going
that that was the beginning my high
school so I grew up in Orange County in
Southern California we actually didn't
even have apcs I actually didn't even
know what CS was until I got to colge
yeah so yeah I guess it shows you don't
really need to be like a a prodigy to
succeed in in Industry cuz you said you
weren't like naturally um you know super
into CS from a from a young age I didn't
know what CS was until I got to UCLA and
even there I started as an Undeclared
engineer just cuz I knew I liked Math
and Science but I didn't know exactly
what I wanted to do and then when I took
our our intro CS classes I thought it
was fun but I still actually I declared
as an electrical engineer I didn't go
into CS um and my reasoning was that I
like video games and I like computers
and I just thought that was you know how
I'm going to get into that later when I
got into like you know Finding
internships and things I realized
actually electrical engineering is maybe
not the way to set myself up for Career
Success so then I ended up switching
into CS which there's a lot of overlap
between e and CS so I it didn't need to
take year with that switch that was
actually in junior year of college so
pretty late that's surprisingly late
yeah but I switched into um computer
science and engineering so I all those e
upper divs I had taken kind of like got
reused and I can go into CS with the
last two years of my college but yeah so
I switched into it pretty late don't
have like a you know storied long tenure
in in CS prior to getting into it in
college yeah I guess we're both proof of
the the contrary of what most people
look back there yeah exactly I I don't
think you need to be like a programming
Prodigy for most stuff in industry and
so I saw you you know once you got into
CS you started getting really involved
like you did the uh Cornell hacking Club
what made you want to to start that so
actually I played soccer at Cornell in
college and then my junior year I came
to the realization that like you know
when you're playing the division one
sport you're spending a ton of time on
it so you're up early you're working out
you're training you're on the bus on
weekends you're traveling whatever and I
finally came to this realization is I
was like Landing internships that I'm
not going to be a professional soccer
player I have no aspirations to be but I
am going to be a professional software
engineer and so why am I dedicating so
much time to the soccer stuff as opposed
to the thing that's actually going to be
fruitful for the rest of my life so I I
quit soccer my junior year and then all
of a sudden I had so much time and so
like at least in a relative sense I had
so much time compared to what I was used
to and so I had been doing a lot of
hacking on the side just building things
that I thought was fun and I decided
this could be a cool thing to try to
expand and so I had done a couple of
Capture the Flag competitions myself and
like entered teams through Reddit and I
figured Cornell's got a bunch of smart
people this could probably be something
that we could do so I set up a handful
of Flyers around the the engineering
quad and next thing you know I had calls
conversations with about 25 people
grabbed a couple of them to kind of be
like the founding quote unquote officers
and then from there we really scaled it
up and had a core team of like 25 people
that competed in ctfs but then had at
some points as many as 200 people who
showed up to weekly like call it
lectures to talk about hacking stuff
that was a ton of fun and I guess as we
see and we might get into later like
with the hello interview stuff I've
always just really loved teaching so
that was a maybe a Genesis for that as
well you know when I was in college or
just in general in my education I feel
like people always told me this advice
of you should get into these leadership
opportunities and oftentimes in high
school it was to just make your college
application look better yeah totally but
I think actually looking back if you if
I look through all the behaviors that
you had to do to start that club get all
the alignment with all the people
communicate and Market it Etc and kind
of be a leader in that space that's
actually a lot of what I think you know
more senior Engineers need to do like
those all those soft skills so I feel
like actually it is a good thing to do
in the long term and I I did some um
leadership stuff as well in college
because I thought it was good for for
interviews but also cuz I I enjoyed
meeting all the other officers in those
clubs and getting involved so and I
think in that experience too beyond all
the leadership stuff which was super
important most of the kids in the club
with me were technically brilliant more
so than me like significantly more so
than me but like we spent all day
hacking and writing code and Building
Things that that were pretty
sophisticated and like even to this day
like you know pretty awesome I look back
at some of those repos and and find it
pretty amazing but you always hear
people recommend doing side projects and
I guess that was my example of that
where it's like I was just working on
something that was fun
with friends who were brilliant and I
feel like that set me up pretty well
eventually going into meta did you have
a side project experiences much going
into I had a few side projects they were
like little things though for instance
there was this one thing that I built I
was in this e club called i e and the
club's lab is only open when an officer
is present you know how do you know if
it's open well maybe you ping people you
have group chats or something see if
it's open but that was kind of
unreliable and slow I wanted there to be
like this status indicator so I built
this occupancy sensor which was
basically just it was like a Raspberry
Pi connected to the Wi-Fi of that lab
sweet if any of the officer's devices I
had like a manual mapping of the Mac
addresses of all their devices if any of
them connected to the Wi-Fi that bot
knew that someone's in the lab and so
you could just ping that slackbot say
hey I think the command was like who is
or something and it'll just give you
like all the officers that are there and
so like yeah that is something that I
did build that I felt like was useful
and it was like a nice side project and
I did remember talking about it in
interview conversations and I feel like
that's such a perfect example because my
suggestion to especially like new grads
nowadays as it pertains to doing a side
project like choosing from some of those
random lists which you see always going
around is like cool but you're not
nearly going to have like you're not
going to be as passionate about it or
want to be working on it later as you
would be something like what you just
describe it's like and so maybe that
would be the concrete advice to to
anybody listening it's in that phase is
like just observe the problems around
you and then build some software to
solve it that's the side project you
should be working on 100% agree I think
there's all this advice on doing side
projects and if you just build one
that's like redis clone or something
like that but no one uses it I guess
it's better than nothing but it's not
letting you do that full end to-end path
of learning and it's essentially the
same as like a college class project or
something that you put on your resume me
you're not going to get nearly as much
out of it highly agree with what you're
saying you did CTF when I think of
really really good technically brilliant
Engineers I think of CTF I think of like
top coder and these competitive coding I
feel like that probably helped you with
leak code what was your experience when
you were interviewing did you feel like
it was pretty smooth when you
interviewed to get your meta job
honestly like not in the beginning
anyway like everybody knows that you
have to leode at school I was surrounded
by a bunch of computer science Majors we
all knew that we had to Le Cod but like
I found it really hard I felt like
people around me found it easier that
might have just been projecting some
insecurities there it might not have
actually been the case but it felt like
that and we would just spend so many
hours every single day in the library
just practicing different problems and
eventually I felt like I got in the
groove but actually maybe funny story
and this is where the first tick of luck
pops in and I'm sure that'll be a
reoccurring theme throughout but meta
came to my campus to interview I think
this still happens periodically but it
certainly happened more then and so they
came to campus I showed up to do my
interview
and the first question that I got was
one that I really would never have been
able to do really struggled with it was
Elite code hard it was super difficult
but the night before when I was studying
I was like let me just look at one more
and I looked at that one and I skimmed
it I didn't do it I just skimmed it but
like I knew the trick and so that
question popped up and had I not skimmed
it I certainly wouldn't have passed
certainly wouldn't have gone on site
wouldn't work at meta you and I probably
wouldn't be having this conversation so
certainly a factor of luck there it's
crazy how much luck can make a
difference there's there's so many
little things that were just
opportunities that happen I'm sure like
the team that you picked or this for
instance just completely change your
trajectory so yeah that resonates and I
think for me for for elak code I was
kind of mid at leak code not very
good I remember my interview season for
junior year I didn't have a great resume
so I I had like one or two companies I
think and the one I ended up getting was
Bloomberg which was in New York yeah and
that was probably a fun experience yeah
it was it was pretty fun although at
that time I was really young so you
can't do a whole lot if you're like a
19-year-old in yeah New York I got
through elak code survived but I
remember that internship the project was
really easy and that I don't mean that
is a bragging thing but it was like a I
don't know only like two weeks of work
even for someone who didn't have context
on the code base so I got it done really
quick and I spent the rest of the time
just grinding leak code CU think okay
I'm going to make sure that that return
that full-time offer that I get is going
to give this amazing company and be so
satisfied with it I'd been practicing
leak code aggressively all day every day
for the entire summer and then I go into
the interviews and I was able to get
interview opportunities with all the
biggest companies because at that point
Bloomberg was a decent name to have UCLA
yeah yeah and UCLA so I was able to get
my foot in the door everywhere but I
failed every single onsite that I got
like I think like when I when I look
back I at the end of the day is just a
wasteland I had two offers one was the
Bloomberg return offer which I didn't
need to interview for and then the other
one was Amazon and that interview Loop
was not an interview Loop it was some
weird sat oh did did you have the online
like simulation thing I did that for
Amazon whereas you're in a full
simulation portal with like a person
telling you to check your email kind of
thing I remember that I don't remember
if that was the year after the one I did
the one that I remember is like they
came to our school and they had a they
booked out a room that could fit
hundreds of people and they all gave us
essentially an SAT like it was uh just
logic puzzles you know that would be
like it would be like a b c d colon
blank and then the multiple choice would
be like is it e fgh h or is it like you
just like complete the pattern kind of
stuff anyway so I I got the offer
through that like weird logic puzzle
thing and anyway at the end of the day I
completely failed all my le code even
though I was grinding and really trying
still not sure what happened in that in
that case but uh yeah ended up accepting
Amazon because I wanted to stay in the
west coast in that case that's so funny
I had a bunch of the interview rounds
too maybe slightly different the
majority went well but there's one that
I failed miserably and I still remember
it to this day because of kind of how
much it shook me up and it was the one I
wanted more than anything it was paler
which at the time in particular like
paler was so cool for whatever reason it
maybe it was just the Cornel thing or
maybe this UCLA paler was so cool and I
went in the interview Loop and they say
you do a first Loop for the on-site and
then they regroup and they call some
names to either like go to the next
round or be released and what they say
is that if your name is called to be
released either you crushed it and
you're just hired or you know you failed
obviously it's probably only true that
you failed but I was convinced by that I
thought I crushed my interview I was in
the first group of names no so I was
like I nailed it and then I just waited
for the call I was so confident and then
two weeks later it told me didn't get it
and I was so heartbroken but oh God the
difference in expectations must have
been crazy totally totally and now in
hindsight it's like oh man I must have
totally just blown it and they were nice
to me making me think Ed did well so
what you're saying about paler
absolutely s tier uh company to go to at
the time this was you were 2017 for
Cornell yeah yeah yeah so I was 2017 for
UCLA and yeah I remember paler was one
company that was absolutely s tier which
I feel like people it's no longer that
prestigious and another one that I
remember was Kora Kora was like oh that
one was really good you should go to
that one that's funny I didn't hear much
about Kora I don't think that was top
the mind for me okay maybe it was like a
California thing the Jane Street Jane
Street yeah Jane Street's always been
all the all of the Quant firms were
really really big I'm sure that probably
still true where you were too but
especially the proximity to to New York
that was really true Cornell at UCLA as
well and when i' I've looked at some
recent day tier lists and aside from the
AI companies coming in those finance
companies are are still you know yeah
they still pay handsomely in cash from
what I understand oh yeah yep I remember
it was like o camel was like the thing
for Jan Street like a little bit yeah
exactly we had an O camel class in
school yeah yeah y y probably just for
that reason okay so you got the meta job
and you graduated and you know so you
started as a newr in ic3 you know I
think one of the first things that
you're faced with is what team do you
pick how' you pick the team that you
ended up going with yeah So Meta used to
Bo Camp they don't have this anymore now
it's team match which is a shame I
understand why they would have gotten
rid of it maybe logistically there's a
lot of overhead you know this well I
love boot both iterations of it but for
those who don't know boot camp was that
you entered kind of Undeclared if you
will to use like college terminology and
you just started by doing a bunch of
tasks and then you eventually started to
whittle down to a handful of teams that
were hiring that you were interested in
you would do some tasks for each of them
respectively and then you got to make
the decision obviously they needed to
also want you it was a bit two-way but
it really felt like you were were in
control you got to try a bunch of things
determine which one you preferred and
then and then join that team and so that
was the case with me and I thought that
I would go the cyber security route
certainly with the the hacking club like
that's what I was passionate about
that's what I was excited about I spent
all summer hacking doing all these
things I thought for sure one of the
reasons I chose meta was boot camp would
allow me to choose a cyber security team
and so I thought I would go that route I
was boot camping with those sorts of
teams and like it just didn't it didn't
feel right cyber secur is really low in
the stack you get a different type of
folk on the teams in those areas they
felt less welcoming to me it felt all a
little bit like more stoic less friendly
I don't know it didn't resonate and then
I came across a team that was nothing i'
had ever considered before but was
working on things that I found so
interesting and this was the General org
was called content integrity and the
org's mission was to build machine
learning models to identify and take
action on violating content and so this
goes from everything from like hate
speech to graphic violence to Sude to
you name it at the time the team that I
joined and was boot camping with was
terrorism and it was a new team it was
being moved from the London office but
at least to the Seattle office where I
was it was a brand new team it didn't
have any Engineers yet it had one
manager and they were the manager of a
different team as well so they were kind
of just standing it up until they hired
a real manager or a full-time manager
and then there was one engineer who was
like half Tech leading it while also
working on another another team I
thought who doesn't want to fight that
sounds that sounds pretty awesome
machine learning Cutting Edge cool
content Integrity had a bunch of young
people that I felt like I could really
relate to made the decision to go that
way was your boot camp in mpk at menla
Park or was it in uh Seattle so the way
that we did it cuz I was out of the
Seattle office we did two two week
stints in mpk and then the rest of it
was out of Seattle so I guess half and
half how did you go about cuz I remember
at the time they gave us a few different
things you could choose from in terms of
you could be an Android engineer you
could be iOS you could be systems which
is just generic term for backend there's
also the other distinction of like do
you want to work on product or do you
want to work on I guess more
infrastructure stuff so were you
thinking about where you wanted to place
yourself in terms of tech stack I think
not Beyond I came in just like thinking
of myself as a backend engineer and so I
just sort of gravitated to the problems
that were like that and I know that now
meta like draws the distinction between
when you interview even sweet products s
generalists obviously there's always
been the front-end iOS you know versions
as well or categories as well yeah I
don't know it wasn't a conscious
decision for me was that something that
that you thought a lot about I think yes
so my team matching situation I mean I
went through through boot camp as well
because I was also at meta I remember
thinking of a few things one was like
the product versus infrastructure
decision and at the time as a newr I
didn't really know what type of work to
expect or what it even meant down the
the road I was just kind of making
decisions without a whole lot of context
based on what I thought sounded cool so
I was thinking oh okay product is it's
like fun and it's like it's like front
end was my understanding and front end
did not appeal to me I was wrong I mean
product can be very deeply Technical and
interesting I was wrong but I ended up
choosing infrastructure even the word
itself sounds Technical and cool totally
yeah yeah I mean there is that sign yeah
exactly so I was like okay I'm I'm going
towards infrastructure teams you know
when you think about infrastructure you
also think about systems a lot of times
and then the other distinction that kind
of like led me to where I was was what
organization that I want to be a part of
so you know there's WhatsApp teams you
could work on the Blue app it's Facebook
you could work on Instagram and
Instagram at the time was the relatively
new acquisition uh Founders were still
there yeah and it was it was hot it was
this cool product you know people people
generally liked Instagram then and the
Facebook ad was kind of this bloated
thing that old people use I don't know I
was thinking okay I want to go to
Instagram and so that's how I ended up
picking an Instagram infra team and I
remember at the time the manager that I
reached out to actually did didn't have
headcount for me but I I begged him
because I said I really want to go to uh
an infrastructure to I really want to
work at Instagram I promise you I'm
going to really work as hard as I can
please please please and he had some
flexibility he was able to I guess
borrow uh headcount from someone or
something because when I met with him he
really felt uh how how Earnest I was
there I think that's one thing that I
learned in my career journey is
oftentimes the best opportunities are
not the ones that seek you out but the
ones that you seek out because the ones
that are seeking you out often times
they're in a you know position of less
strength they just need someone and the
ones that are really great they have all
these people coming to them so you
really got to like battle your way into
them but it was totally worth it and I
absolutely loved that team and I stayed
at it the whole time and that that
moment of agency I'm sure like
translated throughout your your whole
career and that definitely resonated
with me it's it's sort of this aspect of
like you got to go take it it's not
necessarily going to fall on your lap
and so if that seemed like the right fit
for you and you went in and and you sort
of demanded that you take it and it
worked out which is huge yeah yeah
definitely agency is a huge part of
actually capitalizing on opportunity so
much of this stuff is luck and
opportunity and if you have that extra
agency to go and take initiative and
seek things out you can turn things that
were NOS into yeses oh in this case yeah
someone might not have you know might
have politely said oh okay you don't
have head count and like search
somewhere else but I was I was
aggressive starting at meta you're
you're on the team I think you mentioned
to me something all it says in our
outline is penis story I lit I laughed
when I saw that what what is this and
how is this relevant to to your
onboarding at meta so when I when I
first joing the team one of the largest
portions of content integrity was
pornography it was the main thing that
that started Mak sense right making sure
that the site didn't have any
pornography and so like when you're a
new nrad I don't know it's just you
don't expect to see like penises at work
or any nudity at work right um and I
have this distinct memory of the first
time where I had just joined the team I
was trying to get up to speed and I went
up to one of my colleagues who worked on
the porn team again I was the only one
at this point on the terrorism team so I
was kind of relying on them for
expertise and I went over there and sat
next to him to try to ask some questions
and he's got his two big monitors and
one of them's got all the code that he's
been working on and the other one is
just the entire screen filling the
entire screen and I'm like trying not to
look it's incredible shocking and like
jarring to me but this is his every day
you know so to him he didn't even think
twice or notice it I don't know but
there was something about it that was
just like I loved that story afterwards
I went home I told all my friends I
thought it was you know so hysterical
and then it kind of became I don't know
indicative of like the organization and
the team as a as a whole that like you
become desensitized to that stuff you're
doing your job it's it's no longer silly
it's no longer funny but it was a it was
a shocking and memorable moment from my
first stays there that's for sure that's
hilarious just seeing that on the screen
in like a work environment it's kind of
crazy it was really funny and they they
hide Us in that Seattle office they hit
us in the second floor in the corner oh
really you think that was intentional
yeah totally at least that's what the
people before me said was the case so
that nobody ever had to walk past those
desks oh that's so funny and just be
shocked because the nudity is the nudity
is you know Silly and and largely funny
but you know there are plenty of things
that are much more jarring that's
hilarious okay so sounds like your team
had a pretty good like social VI on it
yeah totally when you got there you
mentioned that you were working on the
terrorist side of things um can you tell
a little bit about like the technical
side just in case someone's curious in
the audience like what what exactly you
were working on is like some backend
system or yeah exactly so was backend
system this was mostly hacked is you
know Facebook's types safe PHP maybe not
directly my first project but like my
first substantial project was to work on
this thing that we we named Estuary and
Estuary is the point where multiple
Rivers kind of come and join together um
and ultimately what it was was the
infrastructure in order to detect
terrorist content and so it's this
multi-staged funnel you initially run
some kind of crude checks on content
that are really quick in order to
determine whether they're worth further
considering and running your expensive
models on some photo matching happens at
that point you make a determination
based on the scores the models the photo
matching if you need to take any given
actions if something needs to go to
human review how many human
reviews uh you know combination of those
reviews ultimately to an action as well
and so this was the infrastructure to
facilitate that process and try to make
it as easy as possible for us as the
team to experiment plugging in playing
different models changing thresholds
running AB tests all of these things
kind of getting into the promos like
your first promo was super fast I think
one thing that's interesting though to
to think about is was that something
that you asked your manager about and
you were in touch the whole way or did
it kind of just happen it definitely
just happened that wouldn't be my advice
to people normally but like looking back
at that point in my career I was still I
was new and I was like shy and had my
insecurities like everybody else and
that was a a big moment that stuck with
me there were a couple moments of like
confidence building that happened early
in my career which I think were super
necessary for me to go on and and maybe
kind of achieve the promotions that they
were ultimately achieved and at least in
this case that promo happened my first
half you know six months or so after
after being at the company I never
talked about promo I didn't know how
well I was doing I thought I was doing a
good job but like I don't know relative
to everybody else I figure everyone
around me is really smart and they
certainly were um and then I got pulled
into a room with my manager he gave me a
bunch of compliments tell me I was doing
great I felt really good and then he
said you're promoted and it's nothing I
had even considered he showed me the new
salary the new equity and I was like oh
my gosh holy smokes what just happened
like this is insane I was like shaking
with giddiness uh it was it was a it was
a pretty cool experience but it was a as
I said it was a huge confidence gaining
moment because from that moment on I had
the assurance that I was good and I was
capable and then now I was like sort of
freed of that anxiety questioning
whether or not I was good enough and was
free to just kind of continue to to grow
at that pace and did you intern that
Facebook but beforehand no so I interned
at Zillow beforehand okay the other
confidence gaining moment that really
comes to my mind was actually at Zillow
and so that I entered Zillow now it's
even before meta so I'm like maybe more
insecure working work on on what I need
to work on got my project done quickly
like you said you did with yours at
Bloomberg worked on a bunch of things
that had nothing to do with my product
but were really fun and then I remember
distinctly my manager at the end of at
the end of The Internship both getting
the return offer and then him who had
worked at Google for a long time and
then I was at Zillow saying that I was
the the best intern he had ever worked
with Wow and that was just like the I
think to this day probably the biggest
one of the biggest compliments I ever
got like I was just beaming and I felt
like I felt so good and so confident
coming out of that and so I was able to
ride that confidence into meta and then
of course you still have a bit of the
insecurity and then this moment with my
manager really kind of solidified that
confidence so what is the thing that you
were doing so early in your career that
made both of these
managers you know say you were the best
intern or best you know one of the best
early people they were working with I
think the biggest thing was that I was
just like inquisitive and didn't feel
bounded by what I was told to do and so
at least at Zillow I finished my project
pretty quickly and then I was working on
the rental steam it had nothing to do
with security but security stuff was
interesting to me and I saw all these
posters around the office about how
people shouldn't leave their computers
unlocked when they go to the bathroom or
go to lunch or anything like this people
would leave their screens open security
concern and so I threw together a fun
game where if somebody's screen was open
then you could go to a certain website
hosted internally and then like kind of
get them if you will and so then you had
like a leaderboard and you had like cute
graphs about who left their screen open
and who have been got more than anyone
else and who was getting people and like
became this fun little thing in the
office and that's what I spent most of
my time doing and then I would hang out
a bunch with the cyber security folks
and like they took me to Defcon in Las
Vegas um totally not my team nothing to
do with rentals or anything um but like
I was just looking for other
opportunities to seek out stuff that was
fun to me and the same was true when
first joining meta I think actually the
the article that you published on on
your substack I'm sure we'll link that
below or something talks about my very
first project at meta or again I I
finished it is pretty quickly and then
had all this time to improve it do
things that I thought were fun and
outside of the scope of the original
task you know when we published that
article there was that was probably the
thing people asked the most about which
was you said hey do your work fast and
that gives you this budget of time to
Excel and do all these other things
which lead to the career growth but that
was the big thing that people wanted to
know more about which was how do you get
through your assigned projects and your
initial code and all the things that
expected of you so fast is there
anything that you might say to the
audience for that I understand where the
question is coming from I I hate it
largely because like I don't know and it
almost makes me feel like held up in
this status that I I don't know doesn't
doesn't feel all that deserved I feel
like it just happen I'm interested to
hear your thoughts because I know this
was true for you as well and then maybe
as you're answering it I'll I'll come up
with something that that could be useful
but I know you had the same experience
yeah so I definitely had a similar
experience when I joined Instagram I was
an absolute Workhorse and I was just
churning out anything that anyone gave
me there's two aspects to this one is
doing the work quickly and I think that
to some extent you know having all my
key bindings be super fast and you know
making sure my workflow is really dialed
in like I have everything memorized I
can you know fire off a diff in like 10
minutes or something and really know
where everything is in the code base
and that comes with just spending a lot
of time in like really knowing your area
and becoming kind of like the go-to
person there you know when you first
start someone tells you something you
don't know where it is and you're kind
of just trying to figure out what's
going on but at some point you get so
dialed in that someone says we need to
make that tweak and you know exactly
where is the exact line of code and you
just you can just fire it off so at some
point I got that so dialed in that I was
I looked at my old diff count and it was
like 10 diffs a day at some point cuz I
had a very coding heaving project at
some point I think it's like the second
half of my junior engineer stint um so
there's that aspect but the other thing
too is like if you want an extra 30% of
time you can also just work an extra 30%
um that's the answer nobody ever wants
to hear yeah you don't need to be
brilliant I I'll say um and I definitely
did that I was an absolute monster I
would get in not too early I don't know
like 10:00 a.m. or something but I leave
on the absolute latest shuttle which I
still remember to this day it was like
9:27 p.m. the important thing there must
have been that you were enjoying it
right cuz I think that's the fine line
and that's where the advice becomes kind
of dangerous maybe for sure I think like
because everything was so new and you're
in like this big area and it's you're
it's just fun kind of like getting
really dialed in and firing out all that
code you know as a byproduct whether you
enjoyed it or not if you do spend an
extra 30% a time yeah you can use that
to grow it's almost like this budget of
extra stuff that you can do yeah I guess
there's two ways to it you can you can
really dial in and like you know submit
code more quickly which comes with time
and like really thinking critically
about your workflow but the other thing
too is you can you know work work extra
and it's it's way better working extra
when you enjoy it yeah you're going to
hate your life if you hate submitting
the code but you're doing it anyways
totally totally I think the the two
things that came to mind for me there as
you were sharing all that was the first
one the workflow is so important and for
me it was a memory thing actually don't
I don't have the best memory but I'm
good at using resources in order to tell
me remember things so at my time at
Zillow and at school like I had a I
built a fun little project I think it
was a variant of Lucine at the time I'm
not sure but it was my own like little
personal hosted search engine and I
would just put mark down stuff in there
that I need to remember and then I could
like quickly search it and and find it
fun enough right you can't use that at
meta but it's not all too difficult to
like recreate some variation of that
even with just like a control F and and
some markdown files anytime I solved the
problem I would write it down
and then I never needed to struggle to
solve a problem twice which was really
important and that speeds things up
significantly and then the other thing
that stood out and this I more observed
with mentees that I had or other folks
on the team was that I guess naturally I
just I had the ability to not let things
stop me and so I'm sure this will
resonate with you too but there's plenty
of times for which I would see a mentee
and they got stuck and they'd like try
to research it they would be a little
nervous like do I ask the senior
engineer now or are they busy do I do
this do I do that and I felt pretty
comfortable just spending like an hour
trying to answer the question and then
asking someone you don't want to be that
annoying guy that's always asking things
but like the ability to find the person
at the company that knows and get the
answer from them and this isn't just
true a junior this is true staff and
Beyond I'm sure is a super powerful
skill and that's just like kind of
having the confidence to know it's
reasonable I don't know this let me ask
someone who does and let me write it
down and keep moving that second one is
is huge it can be so impactful because
if you get blocked it could take you
days to do something that someone else
can do in an hour or something you know
if you go to the senior person that
really already knows the code base you
the exact code pointer tell you exactly
what to change instead of you doing like
a blind Brute Force search you can speed
up by days and that is actually way more
impactful than small workflow
improvements and things like that so and
yeah that is kind of like a soft skill
thing where knowing that it's reasonable
to ask knowing how to ask in a way that
is uh welcomed I think that's that's
huge especially for for the early levels
and then maybe the last one here not to
kind of beat a dead horse on this topic
but being able to search the code base I
think that was something that I wasbe
uniquely Adept at early too you know a
meta it's monolith we have the entire
code base at your fingertips and the
chances that you're solving something
for the first time is almost none
somebody has almost certainly done it or
done something similar and so knowing
what to be able to search for and
sometimes this is just like guessing as
to what people might have named
functions or variables and you're
hunting for just that piece of code that
resembles a similar challenge to what
you have in front of you and being good
at that searching process is is honestly
a huge accelerate 100% And if you're
really good at code search it is so
impactful for the later levels too
because often times the later levels
you're just trying to figure out where
to make changes and how to make changes
and figure out ambiguity and like
where's the problem understanding qu
bookly yeah exactly and code search is
like one of the absolute Peak skills to
to really B so yeah that was pretty good
for for the junior side of things moving
on to the next one in terms of promo
from midlevel to senior I'm curious what
is the what were the main differences in
this one and what is the story behind
that promotion I guess the first place
that I would start is that the team had
grown now so we were talking about how I
was the first engineer on the team it
only took a week or two until we hired
the first senior engineer on the team
couple weeks later we had another one
now the team's 8 n it's got the
full-time manager that came in I think
because even though like you know the
team at one point was three senior
engineers and me as the junior engineer
because I was there first even if it was
just a couple weeks I felt like I had
the context and I was like helping them
ramp up sort of was probably more in my
head than anything else but at least
helping them with with context and that
was super valuable like both in terms of
having the confidence and just like
really understanding the the code base
more than more than most people and so
the teamate continue to grow and content
integrity was growing like crazy and we
have more and more violation types that
we needed to support the terrorism team
had been morphed and changed and now
like split into at the time three teams
terrorism child exploitation imagery the
really bad stuff and then graphic
violence and graphic violence was sort
of like the lowest priority of the group
and so it kind of got carved off and my
manager asked me if I wanted to be the
tech lead for the graphic violence team
and I didn't know what tech lead was I
didn't know what that mean it sounded
cool it sounded fancy it turns out it's
not actually even a real thing at meta
like it's a it's not a title that shows
up anywhere it's not formal it's uh you
know it's largely made up in Optics but
like to me it felt so big and cool and
and Powerful I don't I don't love saying
that word but you know it felt it felt
that way and so the team had three
Engineers myself a junior engineer and a
and a mid-level PhD research scientist
and it was the three of us tasked with
solving quote unquote graphic violence
problems at meta and this was the
process of detecting if things were
graphic in most cases putting a warning
screen or an intertial over it uh in the
extreme cases deleting the content and
so like I really took to this this
leadership role so I got to kind of lean
on some of those skills learn during the
hacking Club days and now I'm
proactively setting up weekly meetings
for the team helping management with
laying out our road map even having
one-on ones with both of my teammates
weekly which was a cool and new
experience for me and like this was
really the transformative moment in my
career where I grew more of those
leadership skills and if not grow I was
able to at least Express those
leadership skills and of course there
was a ton of growth in here as well and
then graphic violence like continued to
do pretty well our our stats looked good
and so we took a project that was like
it wasn't dying it was just
underinvested in and we increased our
precision and recall numbers to to to
something I wouldn't be able to quote
now because I don't remember well enough
but we did a great job and I think that
it was on account of my leadership there
and the fact that I was directly leading
other Engineers doing one-on-one setting
team directions road map these are all
qualities of of senior Engineers I can't
remember well enough if we expanded as
well at this point to have more than
just two Engineers before the promotion
it's quite possible that was the case
but I can't remember yeah I think that's
the tldr the promo pack there that's an
absolute no-brainer ic5 promo or senior
promo and that is really interesting cuz
you were just just a year out of college
at that point to be able to step into a
leadership role like that is pretty
extraordinary one thing that I'm curious
about is your manager gave you the
opportunity so it's not like you found
this new thing and said hey we got to do
graphic violence stuff your manager said
hey I got this thing I'm going to trust
this guy with leading this what did you
do to get someone to trust you so early
in your career with you know a more
senior leadership role good
question I'm not sure what I can say is
that it was incredible management and my
manager was was exactly that he was an
incredible leader his his path kind of
up the chain was was fast as well his
influence was was fantastic and I think
this was a moment of him identifying
somebody who had capabilities and giving
them the encourage in the space to be
able to grow into a more full form and
there was plenty of like Hands-On
management as well of course each
one-onone with him I was getting plenty
of tips on on how to become this leader
but at least for me having someone
recognize an ability and then giving me
something that at the time was outside
of my scope and felt Grand was like a
challenge that I felt I I I needed to
repay them and I I needed to kind of
grow into that role and be successful I
think this is really just like a lesson
and fantastic ttbook management of
identify people who maybe have the
capabilities give them more than they
can they can chew maybe I wouldn't say
it that way but give them give them a
larger scope make them feel empowered
and then support them while empowering
them this manager must have seen
something in you that let him think that
you could handle it prior to that
there's something that you did when you
were Junior I guess maybe that's also
why you got promoted so quickly to even
the the mid levels yeah the the the
stepping stone was probably that we
onboarded so many people and like I was
the authority I'd been on the team the
longest and so every person that we
onboarded like I was significant in
their onboarding regardless of their
level and then even beyond their
onboarding you know like I had the
contact so I was the person that people
would come to with questions in order to
to help and to one of the things that
was in the article on your substack like
I was never shy with favors and helping
people and so if anyone came to my desk
with a problem or they needed help with
something then I was eager and willing
to to help out and I'm sure that like
some of these qualities are what kind of
led to to him feeling like he could put
that faith in me yeah yeah exactly
because I've seen people who have the
exact same opportunity they were early
on a team and they even told me they
said this is a good opportunity for me
all the new people coming in I'm going
to onboard them and I this is going to
help I'll be in a a good position and
rather than them riding the wave with
the team growing you know the team goes
uh over them you know they're kind of
they're just Junior engineer that knew
where some of the code was but that's it
but in this case you had the leadership
ability to remain a leader and naturally
too it doesn't sound like you were
really like power hungry and saying I
got to I got to stay on top and you know
you kind of just helped people you knew
everything and you naturally were put in
a leadership positions there were as you
were saying that one thing came to mind
which might be interesting to folks and
that was that there were tensions there
um the one tension that I remember was a
senior engineer who joined the team who
actually ended up being to this day one
of my my best friends in any relative
professional cont context he was a
senior engineer incredibly brilliant guy
a current manager at meta still and I
felt a little like territorial I was
like this is like my project and my
things and like I'm the Little Junior
engineer and he's a sophisticated senior
engineer at the time coming from
Microsoft it didn't last long I remember
I think I had one conversation with my
manager about it but like I I needed to
slap myself across the face and like be
humbled a little bit and he was teaching
me so much so much about like in all of
my code reviews and all of my you know
design meetings design reviews like he
helped me grow so significantly
technically and if I wasn't open to that
I my career likely would have gone in a
different direction and it very well
could have if I didn't kind of a
self-realize that I was having that kind
of negative negative feeling and then to
I'm sure get a a slight slapping across
the face and a polite way from my
manager as well so you felt territorial
but rather than like going and clawing
for and saying this is mine you shared
the scope and actually you two combined
it was like 1+ 1 equals you know three
or something more than yeah and I think
that we had like such an amazing
relationship and he helped me
grow I won't speak for him to any extent
that that that I helped him I think that
might be too large to say but like yeah
well one plus one equal equal three and
we were able to go on and accomplish
great things over the next couple of
years I would also agree I mean in my
career as well I had people who were
working with me that were more senior
they knew way more than me and those
relationships I feel like I owe
everything to those relationship I was
so lucky that these people would spend
the time to work closely with me I would
go and put all this work into the docks
they would eat it alive and you know the
end result is so much better and I
learned so much from them I didn't
really think too much about this is my
thing or whatever and I don't know
exactly what was in each of our
performance reviews like you know did
they get credit for leading and I just
got credit for execution I don't I don't
even know I just put my head down and
said I love working with this guy I'm
learning so much from them and this
project is going amazingly I could point
to a specific person at each promo and
say this person I couldn't have done it
without them and they're they're so
impactful in my growth but also we just
did so much more as a result so that
makes a lot of sense I think whenever
it's getting territorial I think you
know you can think more about how it's
not a zero sum game and you can actually
create way more by not caring about who
does the work but that the work gets
done and it's amazingly high quality
exactly and it's all through a lens of
like self-growth you have to be able to
realize that there's so many things that
you don't know and all of these people
can teach you these things and you have
to be eager to do so as you just said
absolutely one last thing that you said
in this area you talked a little bit
about tech leading and how that was like
a critical part and you define deck
leading is kind of driving the road map
uh you know coordinating with everyone
having one-on ones and working through
others it sounds like I'll just say that
that was also a huge part in my
promotion to senior as well I was not
given it sounds like in your case you
had your manager said hey this scope go
for it and here's people working with
you on it in my case I got a taste of it
with there was some work stream that
we're working on which I kind of became
the backend lead on it naturally it was
just something that was coming together
and there was client we needed client
Engineers we need backend engineers and
I was there first and then as it grew in
importance I was a guy that knew
everything on the back end so there were
you know other teams getting involved
and I was the go-to person and I I was
leading be being a tech lead in that
that space even though I felt it was
kind of stretching my leadership
capabilities I remember a few core
memories of certain meetings where I was
leading it but I didn't feel like a
leader and you I was just doing it
though cuz I knew what I had to do and I
just kind of buckled down and did it but
there's definitely some you know Growing
Pains but uh growing into that role
being a tech lead was a huge part of it
and also I had a intern at some point
which honestly this intern was amazing I
got super lucky this intern basically
showed me the power of I guess like
Leverage or working through others cuz I
I was always a Workhorse and I was
taking on you know three work streams at
the same time and then this guy came
along and I realized oh I can entrust
him with some of this and I can go take
on more stuff and so now I felt like I
was two people at once and I was
shipping twice as much impact and I was
kind of getting the credit for all of it
too because he was like an intern and
you know he'd just be there for a little
bit of time so that kind of got me a uh
a little taste of of like Leverage and I
I something that I I liked a lot for the
rest of my career two things that really
stood out there for me was that the
first one was the power of contact that
seems to be a through line in in both of
ours and there's like that classic
advice of become an expert in something
um so that you're that go-to person in
something and I think that that's that's
great advice for anyone in in their
career if you're the go-to person on
something ideally something valuable and
something growing then that context is
going to be worth so much and then to to
the delegation aspect that's something
that honestly was probably the first
point in my career where things stopped
coming naturally and I remember many
conversations with my manager about like
you need to be able to delegate cuz I
was just like you we like I could just
do it and I could do it quickly so like
why do I need anyone else around to to
help and it was at this moment kind of
around that five promotion just before
just after where that was really getting
beaten into me and similarly to you that
was kind of a huge eye openening
learning when I finally was able to get
that to click like you don't have to do
everything yourself in fact at the
higher levels you can't do everything
yourself and you need to figure out how
to empower people you need to figure out
how to delegate and you need to figure
out how to kind of increase your scope
through others definitely I think that
was the biggest feedback back that I got
once I was senior on how do I get to
staff yeah it was like the buzz word was
scaling yourself like you you got to
scale yourself I'm really thankful that
I had that experience with the intern as
a senior or growing into senior because
that was like the name of the game to
kind of be able to take on more scope
than I could physically deliver okay
before we go to the staff stuff I guess
last thing on the five stuff at this
point you're kind of more plugged into
the industry did you start talking to
your manager about promo this time or
yeah yeah now like I had a great
relationship with my manager he was
always looking out for me and trying to
push me to move as quickly as possible
but similarly like we'd have those open
conversations you know like we're
looking for a promotion by this day
let's make it happen here's what has to
happen in order to accomplish it and so
it was like a much more honest and open
conversation at that point I talked to a
lot of my friends when I was at meta in
my boot camp class who didn't have the
same experience they didn't have the
same promotion growth and largely they
didn't have a manager that was
advocating for them to the same degree
that I had and so my advice to them
which was maybe a little bit silly
because I don't know that I even did all
this all that much certainly not the
beginning but was like that they really
needed to self- Advocate and like you
have to have those conversations with
your managers this is when I want to be
promoted to five by and this is what I
think I need to do do you agree where
are the gaps and it's like an awkward
conversation cuz it's setting yourself
up it's vulnerable like but you have to
have it you have to have that
conversation and you want to hear the
bad news if there is bad news you'd
rather hear it now then come promo day
when you're expecting something 100% my
manager at this point was you know one
of my absolute favorite managers love
him and learn so much from him he was
never pushing me hard for promo but he
was very supportive when I asked for it
and so I guess in my experience I was
more of like the I advocated for myself
pretty aggressively and it it definitely
made a difference and it's not that my
manager was ever not supportive it's
just that he wasn't coming to me and
saying hey let's let's do the promo
here's the date I would come into the
conversation say hey what do I have to
do to get promoted I'm super motivated
I'm loving this work what does it even
look like at the next level and me just
constantly going in and because I was a
high performer I think that also helped
me a lot because my manager had strong
reason to kind of you know make sure
that I was happy with my growth and and
everything and you know as I'm growing
too I'm I'm helping them get way more
stuff done so there's just like a lot of
alignment and incentive um there totally
I think that your experience there is
definitely the one that most people can
try to to learn from there and what you
just described I didn't put into action
until later on it wasn't until I have a
different manager when I was like
shooting for the the seven path that we
were really that I was more advocating
for myself as opposed to and my manager
was still great and and on my team of
course but it wasn't being as led by my
manager at that point yeah definitely
and also I think the you know some
managers are just more they have more
things on their plates it's not like
they they don't want you to they just
aren't focused on it potentially it just
makes you get a lot more lucky with your
promos if you're you're focused on it
yeah and by the way to luck I think that
manager that you had that was also like
opportunity and luck to some extent
right like you could have had a manager
that actively disliked you and even
though you're a killing it you might
have been delayed on the promos or might
not have got the opportunity to begin
with so 100% yeah that's it that's a
huge portion of it having the right
manager is is is huge and I think
there's there's probably there's two
pieces there you certainly need to have
the right manager it's also true that
managers are taught to like invest in
their High performers both of those
things need to be true you need to be a
high performer so your manager wants to
invest in you and then your manager
needs to be fantastic in order to kind
of push that rate of acceleration if
you're finding that you're not
performing high and you're not getting
attention from your manager that's
probably why as maybe hurtful as that is
to say and it's like you need that
self-recognition to realize the first
thing I need to fix is to become a high
performer in order to kind of deserve
that that attention and then you know
then you can be a little bit more
forceful with them about their about the
next steps I don't know too many people
who are high performers that are having
maybe not getting a whole lot of
attention unless there's some crazy
thrash situation where people keep
leaving and yeah which which also does
happen so but like managers are
incentivized to grow their team if the
more promotions they give that are
warranted obviously and it meta they
have to be warranted they go through it
a pretty rigorous process but like
they're rewarded for growth within their
team and how many higher levels are
within their team and so like they're
looking for the ones that are excelling
so they can invest their resources in
those in order to also help themselves
like it's it's the reality and it's a
it's the right incentive structure too I
don't think that it's devious so talking
about staff promotions and I think this
is the part that I think a lot of people
are most interested in cuz it's
ambiguous I guess the thing that I'm I'm
curious about to start is what kept you
at the company on the same team because
when I think to my peers a lot of them
had left their initial team within 2
years or they switched companies uh so
what kept you there yeah I guess the
short of it was that I just really loved
it actually I wasn't hyper optimizing
for growth like the growth stuff was
happening and it was fun it was great
and I loved it and I was trying to push
for promotions but like I was just
really enjoying what I was doing we were
working on really cool things and I felt
like deeply like I was having an impact
in the world whether it was terrorism
graphic violence I worked for smaller on
the CI stuff like it was deeply
fulfilling and it was exciting and then
at least the fact that the team was
growing so quickly and that content
Integrity the organization kept growing
and it meant that despite the fact that
I never switched teams I went from
working on terrorism to CI to graphic
violence to we'll talk about here in six
some other stuff and so I never made a
conscious change but I had three
managers I had different teams the
engineers around me were all coming and
going like there was enough dynamy to
keep me interested I think that started
to fade towards towards the end of my
career at meta and then obviously a
change was made but at this point I was
just loving what I was doing so there
was no there's no consideration I think
for me you know I stayed much longer
than uh all of my friends I think a lot
of my friends they went off to do
startups or or whatever I'm I'm curious
to hear from you and I don't know if
it's now or if you want to talk about
this later but at least fairly recently
you made the change I did I wonder how
you reflect on that if if you wish you
made it earlier kind of how the change
how the change went in terms of your
growth not just in your career growth
your technical growth all those things
yeah and we can definitely talk about
that I think up until the Staff point I
was hyper optimizing for for career
growth and I I loved my work at the same
time too don't get me wrong but I was
always thinking you know how how can I
grow faster I think I was pretty
ambitious when it comes to to that sort
of thing every year I would think you
know what can I do to grow faster what
is the next thing and the answer was
always well stay here that there's
another promo right on the table all
right the opportunity is clear yeah the
opportunity was clear and I was loving
the people I was working with and the
work so I actively thought about it and
decided to stay and I felt like that was
also uh powerful in making me feel uh
satisfied and fulfilled in my work was
that every time I consider I was
thinking yeah this is I'm doing the
right thing in the right place and so
that's kind of what kept me working on
the same team for so long it makes sense
and I think that that's actually it's
like I was the same way and it's and
it's a blessing and it was right and it
was great for our careers but in
hindsight like there is a a slight
negative to it it's almost like this
trap of that next thing is so close so
keep going to it and I wonder if at
least like as a meta Point that's meta
not as in the company but you know what
I'm saying it's better to switch like a
little bit sooner for for technical
growth I don't know it's a balance as
trade-offs at least reflector on myself
there is a lot of trade-offs that come
with it I will say staying until ic6
especially with the trajectory I have I
I don't have a whole lot of regret with
it I look back and I I AB absolutely
loved being plugged into this maybe it's
just my personality but knowing that
there's something right in front of me
grinding towards it there's all these
things I'm growing towards the next ring
in the ladder right yeah I felt like I
was playing a video game or something
and it was just so you know you talked
about that first fromo you got and you
felt so giddy yeah I was I was chasing
that high all the time no totally I
definitely think like to ic6 it was a no
verer especially with the trajectory I
think it would be different if it was
grueling and there was a lot of
uncertainty and things but I do feel
like locking in the ic6 growth so
quickly well it definitely helped
financially there's no doubt but also I
think a lot of the higher level
behaviors are the most satisfying for me
personally like I I enjoy working
through others and leverage and as an
ic6 you define the direction and that's
very satisfying to me rather than taking
Direction yeah let's talk a little bit
about the ic6 promo for you I'm curious
what was the anchor project that got you
promoted maybe you can tell us a little
about the story at the time I guess the
turning point was so I'm still the the
tech leader of the graphic violence team
so I guess timing wise let's see the
first promotion was a half from four to
five then was two halves a year and then
this one was three half so it went one
two three and so we're probably halfway
through at this point maybe a little bit
before halfway so maybe the first of
those three halves and um the tragic
incidents in New Zealand the Christ
Church shooting I don't know if this is
something that you remember from the
news at all but it was March 19th or
March 15th 2019 and somebody live
streamed the shooting of a mosque in
Christ Church New Zealand killed 51
people on live stream and as the tech
lead for the graphic violence team I was
heavily involved in in Facebook's
technical response to this it was all
over the news it was a horrible
atrossity and we blew it we missed it
like we allowed this to be live on the
platform for n and a half minutes as
opposed to detecting it much sooner and
then beyond that copies of it kept
spreading like crazy so people would
download the full video I think he also
streamed was it twitch something else um
anyway you know the videos just
continued to be spread around our
platform and this was bad and so I think
that this happened my memory serves me
correctly sometime in the evening 5 or 6
p.m. I think I'd already gone home at
this point and I got the phone call that
it was an emergency probably from my pm
at that time and like we were in the war
room and so I'm sitting in the war room
with the the VP of Integrity with head
of content policy at Facebook and like I
was the technical head here my manager
at the time if I remember correctly was
on paternity leave so it was like you
know there were plenty of people around
to support don't get me wrong but I kind
of had a significant role to play there
and so there were many nights staying up
through most of them figuring out what
to do training models kind of overnight
on the spot in order to detect different
variations of these things making
adjustments to our content detection
algorithms in our photo Banks video
Banks respectively and like that was
that was significant it gave me a lot of
visibility and I wasn't thinking about
promotions obviously at the time I was
thinking about like the families of the
people who had this video being
circulated and the atrocity that it was
and everybody that we were working with
was thinking about you know that context
just how awful the situation was and
that we wanted to be a part of the
solution so I spent a lot of time on
that and then ultimately we came to the
conclusion as a company and my manager
is now back from paternity leave and I I
only learned how strongly he petitioned
for this afterwards at the time I
thought I had a larger role in this at a
n side I did but regardless the
recognition for the company was that we
were underinvested in our ability to
detect these sorts of worst of the worst
atrocities in real time on live video
and so my team in graphic violence put
most of our resources onto photos and
videos that were not live and this is
just a it's a different fundamental
challenge so we decided to create a new
team and this team was called realtime
integrity and its goal was to detect in
real time things like murders and
suicides on live video which is a
horrible thing that you even need to do
in the first place but unfortunately it
was necessary and so the team was
created and at the time of creation it
was was me and the PM and they basically
said this is your guys's problem figure
out the scope figure out how many
Engineers you need figure out what you
need to do figure out the road map and
like have at it and so this was totally
Green Field and it was a super fun
challenging thing to work on it was
super fulfilling it was super exciting
we started to higher up slowly uh for
the first half or so we only had two
other Engineers other than me so three
engineers in total and our progress was
really slow actually like we were having
a really hard time detecting any of this
content it's it happens so infrequently
and so you know you're caught in these
terrible situations of what do you do
you train on the couple of examples that
you have and then obviously they were in
your training data so you're overfitting
to them so the fact that you detect them
now is not representative of anything
but we don't have any other examples to
evaluate ourselves on so like it's a
measurement Nightmare and then the only
way that we can know if we're doing a
good job or not is that the next
atrocity happens and we get the phone
call that we blew it again so it was
like it was stressful and progress
wasn't being made at the pace that we
wanted it to be made at but then two
large things came that changed that the
first was the need to solve the
measurement problem and so in order to
do this this was sort of my largest
project at the time and it grew even to
an an organization wide project later on
an Integrity wide project later on and
we called it golden set recall and it
was basically the idea that like we we
went through a bunch of effort in order
to curate a set a golden set of content
that we needed to be able to evaluate
ourselves on this was all of the past
atrocities that have happened since live
video went live in 2007 or whatever it
was 2011 uh 12 maybe anyway all of those
and then like this is the set that we're
going to evaluate ourselves on by way of
actually restreaming content so we'll
have holdout content that needs to uh
that we need to evaluate against and
we're going to set up the infrastructure
since that such that Bots will
legitimately restream this content in
order to test holistically our
infrastructure not just our models we'll
legitimately restream this content on
Facebook comments will come in at the
right time all of these different things
and then importantly this needs to be
like fully isolated it needs to be on
real Facebook so that it tests our real
infrastructure but obviously if anybody
saw any of this it would be an absolute
Nightmare and so that was the challenge
and once we had eyes we knew how we were
doing and what we learned was that like
our recall at the time was 9% this was
for suicide specifically for which we
had more data for and so we had 9%
recall on live suicides on Facebook this
is this is bad this is this is not good
at all so we contined to iterate from a
modeling perspective we're doing like
fancy things from modeling perspectives
is's a lot of uh assistants from the AI
org as well like they're doing a lot of
the core embeddings and then you know
we're doing the applied ML on top of it
you know we're doing sophisticated
sequencing temporal modeling and
nothing's really happening and then I
had the idea which is so obvious in
hindsight but I looked at enough of
these examples that we were missing as
they were coming in every day and I
realized that you look at the comments
and the comments read don't do it your
family loves you like please no these
comments are indicative and the people
who are posting the comments know of the
atrocity long before our sophisticated
models were able to figure it out and at
the time we were so focused on pinching
pixels and Audio Waves that we weren't
focused on the thing that was obvious
and right there kind of beneath our nose
the entire time and so we updated the
models to take into consideration these
kind of temporal comment signals and it
was a revelation like we went from 9 to
50 55% recall almost overnight and then
now we had a feedback loop now the model
is better and it's actually detecting
these things far more than you would
ever imagine would actually be on these
platforms and now we have more training
data and now we can continue to iterate
and we have a foothold and by the time I
left we were into the mid 90% on recall
which was which was a huge success and
so to tit all back to the to the promo
the promo came kind of maybe halfway
through that story where we were just
starting to see progress we had a metric
we had a way to evaluate comments were
successful and so I think my promo
packet was something on the back of was
able to step up in a time of need for
the company do all of these fantastic
things to help us when we were in crisis
and then created largely and led a new
team in order to solve this problem
moving forward and has up until this
point the point of the promotion made
significant progress and I think at that
point it was you know like the 9% to 60%
or something I mean that's huge impact
so the ic6 scope in terms of the impact
side of things was absolutely clear you
said something there about your you were
just given the opportunity to create a
team from scratch as an IC how big did
that team end up being and how was that
process by the time I left the team had
just recently split into two two of
eight each so 16 total at the at it at
its peak real time integrity was
something around 12 to 14 engineers at
this point I you know I was two years
into being staff or so so this isn't as
close to the promo path by promo time
maybe the team was four or five
Engineers but it continued to grow and
at first it well we weren't sure if it
was going to be like a dud project you
know for through the first six to eight
months six months maybe but once we
started to get that acceleration then it
was something that the company and
Leadership wanted to invest resources in
and fortunately it was sort of a pet
project of like the VP and director of
the org because of you know Mark was
breathing down their neck about how
horrible this was that we allowed this
to happen we can't allow it to happen
again so we were getting resources
accordingly man for an ic5 to just be
trusted with this blue ocean of build
this team for like a top priority for
the org I like that a directors paying
attention to is definitely uh a huge a
huge opportunity who was the decision
maker that that gave you that
opportunity it was that the director or
was that your your direct manager be
honest I don't know so there's like the
visibility that I had and to which this
felt so cool I felt like I was just
given so much scope I felt like I
advocated for it based on what happened
you know during the incident and I think
all of this was true in part but as I
said I learned that behind the scenes my
manager was doing a ton of advocating
for this new team and my guess would be
that in part of his advocating or
advocacy it was let's kind of let Evan
and the pm at the time like have a shout
at this and of course he's there and
close by and helping it's not like you
know your manager is certainly involved
yeah like I said I think he did far more
behind the scenes than I appreciated at
the time but it felt to me and as it was
written in my promo packet like this was
a moment of proactivity uh for me to
like kind of largely suggest the
creation of a team and Lead its
Inception got it okay and so would have
been a case of uh I guess creating this
scope then as as the IC uh Tech lead
involved when you look back on that I
guess what was like the most important
behavior that kind of got you promoted
because I think you've laid out the
facts of what happened but you know what
was like the skill that you kind of
needed that maybe made it the biggest
difference the biggest thing was the not
being afraid to try the simple and
obvious thing this or in general and all
the teams that I was on and certainly
real time Integrity like I was
surrounded by MLP s and it was
interesting on these teams and that
there was like a ton of ambiguity you
know like I largely did a lot of the
infrastructure but I spent a lot of time
training models too and fine-tuning
Hyper parameters and doing feature
engineering just alongside and them and
they would do infrastructure things too
like when you were on the team your
title didn't really matter we all did
things you know you lean towards your
expertise but nonetheless and so I just
had this really unique opportunity where
I was surrounded by brilliant people who
they absolutely were brilliant but they
sort of had like horse Blinder to the
effect of focusing on how to optimize
the model in the most sophisticated
technical means possible so that they
could write a research paper and make
progress in that way and this was like
really fun cuttingedge modeling that we
were doing it was interesting but I
obviously by the nature of having less
expertise there was less focused on
those things and I had only one thing on
my mind get this number from nine to
something higher and what is it going to
take to do that and while most people
were focused narrowly on the model
improvements I was focused on the
holistic problem and this allowed me to
see those Simple Solutions like for
example the comments and so in hindsight
it's a no-brainer but I think this is
kind of Representative of much of big
Tech at times that the people that are
there are brilliant and want to solve
hard complex technical challenges and
those who are able to take a step back
view the problem more holistically and
then propose the solutions that
regardless of their technical
sophistication are going to make the
largest progress on the goal of times
Excel and I think that was true not just
in this moment but but throughout much
of my career is that is that something
that resonates with you yes that that
definitely resonates and when I think
about my staff promotion I ended up
writing a blog post um about it which I
can kind of Link in the show notes about
the optimization but the tldr is on a
high level the optimization that I I
actually did was trivial it was I I was
kind of I guess maybe uh you know in a
tech lead role trying to figure out
what's the best way to optimize our
compute efficiency for for everything
for all the workloads that were being
spent on uh processing Instagram video
en codings that was an area where we
didn't look for a long time because as a
growing small company is like Instagram
you just throw more machines at it and
it's usually fine but at some point I
think this was around covid there was
too much demand for our platforms
because people were using it so much
while they were all Sheltering in place
and so actually it became critical that
we needed to uh improve our computer
efficiency and I got lucky because I was
looking into that when it became
business critical and I was kind of
already there and kind of playing around
tinkering in an area where no one had
looked at it just because I thought it
would be fun I that it just sounds cool
you know compute efficiency I was like
yeah this is awesome let's make it
better and then so there's so much money
to be saved
exactly I just thought oh there's this
big opportunity and this work is going
to be so cool and so I just started
looking into the area and kind of
digging into like what what would it
look like to make this sufficient
because this is something that we've
never really looked at and I you know
listed out all the ideas and I booked
meetings with the most brilliant
Engineers that I was working with that
also contributed to these brainstorms as
well and when we put everything out the
the most impactful idea was the most
obvious easy thing to do it absolutely
trivial it was like on a high level I
could just explain it as we just didn't
do some redundant work that we were
already
doing and it probably wasn't the first
thing people considered yeah there's
there's a lot of other things we could
definitely be doing yeah this this
project didn't seem that cool yeah it
definitely resonates that you know as an
ic6 engineer or just generally as an
engineer you focusing on actually what
matters and what's impact ful is the
absolute number one thing that's going
to grow your career and it's not always
the uh technically complex solution that
is the shortest path to having impact
and the people who have the initiative
to drive the impact regardless of what
it takes to do it are going to be the
people who are rewarded because
everything is proportional to your
impact so yeah that definitely resonates
to me in terms of doing the simple thing
it's actually it's it's a benefit this
simpler the optimization is the way that
I look at prioritization is it's kind of
like the the impact throughput that
you're having where you can think of
this as like a fraction and the the
numerator is like how much impact is
there but obviously the denominator is
like how much effort and time and
complexity is this thing going to be and
actually if someone tells me this is I'm
going to have the biggest impact with
like a oneline change that is just not
doing some additional work it's amazing
I prefer that to the crazy you know
year-long project that's like super
complex and adds all this maintenance
that that was one place that was one
place where meta's culture excelled and
I don't know to the extent that this has
changed since I've left of course you're
still there so you can speak to this but
I know at other companies if you're the
guy who made the oneline change and it
had huge impact you're going to be
rewarded proportional to the difficulty
the oneline change right whereas at meta
that wasn't the case like it was like
you had huge impact and nobody else
thought to that one mind but you did and
so you're rewarded for it and that
creates this culture that's so important
of go find the impact it doesn't have to
be the hard crazy thing it doesn't have
to be a lot of work find the impact and
have positive impact for the company and
you're rewarded and so that's always
been a fantastic thing about medic
culture yeah absolutely that's the
number one thing that I enjoy about meta
culture and I think no matter where I'm
working I'm always going to take that
with me for the rest of my career just
that impact is everything I don't care
how it happens who does it it's just
let's just get the job done and make
things better and in that case sounds
like you you were trusted with the scope
the team grew to something where it's
you're basically doing an ic's job and
you delivered massively more than anyone
expected so I think the ic6 promo made a
lot of sense one thing that I think is
unique about your career path as
especially starting from four and onward
or midlevel to staff is it seems like
like your management Shane was trusting
you almost as a manager they were
telling you to give us how many
headcount you need and you're having
one-on ones with people and you were
growing people in that sense did that
come naturally to you and am I seeing
that uh right like that you were not
purely doing IC stuff you were also kind
of an extension of your manager and
doing some management stuff yeah I think
that's fair and actually I wanted to
jump in and mention this so I'm glad
that you brought it back like
Technically when defining well I guess
you can't say technically cuz Tech lead
isn't a Define role but traditionally
Tech lead is that you're setting the
technical direction for the team and so
as you just described my role had like a
lot more of a people aspect maybe than
was traditionally the case and of course
these Engineers were still having one-on
ones with their real manager their real
manager was determining their promos and
whatnot but certainly when I was senior
and absolutely when I was at staff
absolutely when I was at staff I was
like kind of explicitly in those
conversations to help my manager have
visibility and make determinations about
the given engineer on the team's
performance reviews even to the point
where at least we attempted to have me
attend a uh a calibrations and an
ultimately ended up getting shut down
for whatever reason from from the
director as an ic5 or as an IC as an ic6
as an ic6 but yeah why that ended up
happening I'm not sure I think I really
enjoyed it and like I took it so
seriously like I I really wanted to be
good at it and so I was really observing
what my manager was doing I read the
making of a manager when I became when I
became the tech lead of graphic violence
I read that book thinking like I really
got to learn how to kind of lead right
and it was a great book and yeah I don't
know I just I took it seriously and I
think the fact that I excel did it and
importantly I don't want to speak for
any of the engineers that I worked with
but I was never aware of any time where
people felt uneasy with my leadership or
like I wasn't on their team and
supporting them and I think that's where
those things will typically go wrong is
there's either like components of
competitiveness jealousy aggression
whatever it is where it's like why are
you in between me and my manager and why
do you say what is going on and do you
have my best interests like why am I
navigating with this person now and I
think probably subconsciously cuz I
didn't do this explicitly necessarily
but I just understood the value of being
on everyone's team and on everyone's
side and so to the favor stuff that we
were talking about to just generally
being nice and wanting to come to work
like I thought and some people listening
to this that were my old colleagues May
disagree with some of these statements
but I don't know of any that would like
I was everyone's best friend and I was
trying to help everyone and they knew
that I had their best intentions in and
that was genuinely true there was nobody
that I felt kind of sour about in any
way and I think that allowed me to
continue to have that role without there
being any significant tension because I
could imagine any engineer feeling
uncomfortable with it would raise that
to a manager and then the manager would
recognize that and kind of pull back
that responsibility I gu was able to to
navigate it cautiously enough they all
had trust in you it sounds like because
I mean not only were you genuinely
caring and thinking about their growth
but also you were someone who was very
technical competent and I'm sure they
had seen that you had demonstrated
yourself repeatedly so because I've seen
the case where someone who doesn't do
all that soft skills stuff or the behind
the scenes stuff and they have trouble
with the transition into a more
leadership role and so I think that's
something that you did that was
outstanding and I think was a large part
of your success in these leadership
roles maybe maybe the the last thing on
this point that's really interesting
that just came to mind for those
listening at meta your level isn't
public and so often times it's known
within teams and on different teams it's
known to varing degrees at my team at
least like it wasn't it wasn't really
talked about of course you knew the
levels of the people like I knew the
levels of the people on my team for
example because I was involved in their
promo packets or whatever else it may be
of course but like I at least was under
the impression often times that those
that I was leading or those on my teams
did not know my level and so there's no
fall back of like I'm ic6 you you should
listen to me it needed to be earned
every day right like they didn't know
what I was and they could guess or not
guess but like they're probably doing
the math and at times I had my own
insecurity of like people are looking at
my profile and saying that I've been at
the company three years like and I have
all of this responsibility they're
probably writing me off or feeling some
type of way about it or whatever else
and it kind of kept me hungry because I
couldn't rely on this like oh just look
at my title and see that I have a bigger
title than you so now listen and I think
that's another thing that that is
fantastic within meta culture I agree
100% And I I think prior to me
transitioning to management and actually
knowing everyone's levels you just have
this gauge this this high level thinking
of like you know let's say I had joined
your team and you're just outspoken in
all the meetings these get a sense of
okay this person knows what they're
doing and I start to get credibility if
you say things that are right all the
time like okay this guy you know I trust
this guy this is good and if he has
proposed an idea I'm more likely to
believe it and that sort of thing when I
became a manager and I knew everyone's
levels afterwards there was no surprises
on my end even though I didn't know
anyone's level I think if I you asked me
to guess it I might have been off by
plus or minus a level but when I became
it I was thinking that makes sense this
guy is amazing he deserves that level
and you know these people yeah so I I I
kind of I like that and I think one
large part of growing the ic6 too is
also being able to influence without
Authority you people don't know your
level so that's one thing you also they
don't report to you you're not their
manager directly in any way you know to
get five people to go in your direction
you got to convince them that you know
what you're doing that you have a good
idea that they can trust you and you
have to do all of that without relying
on some contrived thing that's like hey
I'm a higher level than you you need to
do what I say you just need to be right
a lot and that's how you build trust
totally yeah exactly exactly right about
management by the way so sounds like you
you were considering ic7 I guess before
we talk about you leaving meta did at
any point you consider going to
management so I actually thought that's
what I would do I thought I would go to
six and then switch over to management
and then for whatever reason maybe
similar to what you were describing
before like the opportunity to seven
seemed clear enough and there's a lot of
work that comes from being a manager I
talked to a lot of my friends who had
recently made that transition actually
that first engineer that I had described
earlier the senior engineer uh who I had
built a built a good relationship with
after kind of our initial
competitiveness or my received
competitiveness uh he certainly did not
have the competitiveness he had recently
transitioned to be a manager and I was
hearing from him and like this stresses
that come with the manager you know like
you're you're directly responsible for
people you have to take care of their
issues and the BS that comes up and it's
a large weight and I all of a sudden
found myself in this like amazing place
where my organization had grown
tremendously I was sort of like the
entry point of knowledge in many ways to
the organization I had VP and director
visibility and all these cool projects
that I could work on across not just
content Integrity my or but Integrity
the the larger org of several thousand
people yeah I decided that let me get to
seven and then I'll think about
switching maybe over to to M2 because
then I would avoid the petty problems
because m1's who are reporting to you
typically have less small problems than
you know Junior and mid-level folk
reporting to you yeah for me I was faced
with a similar decision I think I got to
six and I was think thinking okay do I
do seven or do I go to management and my
manager told me and he was absolutely
right in that he said if you stay as IC
there's a path for ic7 I I can see it
it's not that ambiguous you just it's
continuation of your existing role and
we need it if you become a manager it's
a lot more based on opportunity and I
just don't know like there there's a you
you may get promoted you may not like
there's just no not a whole lot of uh
deterministic control in your your promo
that being said I went to management
anyways because you you stayed at ic6
for a bit right you didn't immediately
make the change for a bit not
immediately but I also after some time I
switched to tlm which was still kind of
uh you know icy for a bit and I had a
small team of maybe a few people may
four five maybe for people who don't
know Define tlm yeah tlm is a tech Le
manager which is a role that some
companies have where you are I'll
describe it on a high level you're 70%
IC 30% manager where you your
contributions are still carried as being
an IC but you have a small team of
people that report to you often they're
a team of Specialists or something like
that where everyone's like kind of
focused on like a very narrow
technically challenging problem and so
that's kind of like what I was doing and
then I told my manager that you know
kind of want to grow more as a manager
and eventually uh pivoted a little more
into a org leader which is just a
traditional manager but yeah I I
switched to manager well one because my
intrinsic desire was let's learn this
new set of behaviors I feel like this
will be cool learn a lot but the other
thing is I felt like if I grew to ic7 I
would become a snowflake or like I
become this this very unique tool for
very very big companies and I'm always
thinking about the long term and I just
thought that okay I go to seven and then
what now I'm I I kind of like narrowed
the opportunities that I can fit into
and I'm only useful in a handful of very
very big companies and even more so if I
were to grow to ic8 and at that point
you kind of the the show ends there some
people get to ic9 but it's for the most
part that's the end of your your growth
and at a certain point you've handcuffed
to that given company yes like in meta's
case if you make it to IC not only do
you have so much Equity that to leave
would be crazy but you're not going to
get hired especially you know at our
trajectories let's just say
hypothetically I don't know the number
of years but eight years or something to
to IC to be eight years into your career
and go over to Google or whomever else
and say I'd like an ic8 they'd they
laugh at you right so and you wouldn't
want to go take the the huge decrease in
pay and lose all that Equity so you're
just like you're kind of stuck is an I8
at meta forever yep definitely and
because a lot of your impact is coming
from your credibility within this or you
go to Google you don't necessarily have
that and so I just felt like although I
might have been happier in the short
term going to ic7 and all of that I
decided let's try out this new path and
let's learn management and I felt like I
had a unique opportunity to do so not
always easy to transition to management
especially as such a young IC at the
time so I felt like okay let's let's go
for it and what what what stands out as
the of single biggest learning so far
well first thing I'll say is for the
people out there who are thinking about
career growth and all that what my
manager said was right my career my your
career as a manager is kind of
proportional to the number of recursive
reports you have and you know unless
your team is growing quickly you're not
going to get to that next thing so you
kind of couple yourself to the growth of
your org which can be a good or bad
thing especially now at metan across all
the big companies with the age of
efficiency exactly exactly the or CH got
squeezed yeah yeah yeah exact opportun
there five years ago the trees were just
growing and growing and growing y y
exactly so I've gotten very lucky in my
career I could say this is uh me giving
back a little bit I switched to
management at the time where it was
maybe an unlucky time to do so but yeah
other than that I mean a lot of the
things that you hear stereotypically are
also true I think what you mentioned
about dealing with people problems like
a lot of the I guess sevs or like major
incidents that I think about now are
this person is you know has some issue
with that team and he's unhappy or
something like that and then another
interesting thing is your your work
hours become like a solid block of
meetings from like 9 to5 as a as a tech
lead or as an IC I would you have like
dis fragmented meetings along the day
and then I would work like kind of later
Into the Night On My IC stuff so maybe I
worked a larger number of hours but I
had more flexibility and control as a
manager is just you know you you log in
you attend those meetings you log out
because I can't really do a whole lot
without people and so I kind of you know
it's not like I can just grind into the
night get things done so and if you are
doing that you're filling out
performance reviews or something which
isn't exactly fun to be doing L yeah
yeah that's that's coming up soon
performance re that's the chore that you
that's definitely maybe the grindi time
of my career is when there's performance
reviews you just non-stop meetings all
day writing all night meetings all day
writing all night brutal um yeah so
there's the manager I don't I don't envy
you
sir yeah I'll say uh being an IC does
give you that flexibility that makes
life a little more you have more control
of your own stuff okay so you you got to
staff and then you left what uh what
made you want to leave meta so I stayed
for another
a little over year and a half which felt
significant like I I feel like I mean
almost half of my time not quite but uh
a third of my time was spent there and
like the team continued to grow was
doing all of that crossw workg stuff
that I had mentioned as I said the team
split into two a new manager had come in
that was a really cool relationship
because he came in and immediately it
was like you know and he said this in
his quotes like this is this is your
team I'm not here to take it you know
you and I are Partners let's figure out
how we can grow this and do all of this
together and that that was like a really
cool opportunity where I saw more of
that management angle in particular and
we were shooting we were shooting for
seven like I really wanted to continue
at this point the one half two half
three halves and then now four halves
seven right and that was that was like
our plan you know we were going to get
try to go up for it and who knows if
we'd come up just shy or not you know
and if we did we'd go the next half so I
thought that was going to be it like you
make a ton of money at seven life's
great you making a ton of money of
course at six and all these things
that's what I thought the path was but
that first manager who I had mentioned
have mentioned a number of times now who
I massively respected had the biggest
influence in my career most brilliant
person I've ever worked with respected
infinitely um he started messaging me he
had moved to a different team at this
point he was an M2 elsewhere and this
was when web 3 was becoming all over
agage a little fun yeah exactly exactly
so people who bought into it as I it at
the time this was like and it may still
happen but like the next iteration of
the internet a decentralized better
internet right with all the benefits
that come from it and so in college I
really liked crypto Ean goon Seer was my
the adviser of our hacking Club I was
also a TA for him and he's really
influential in the crypto Community um
he's the current CEO and founder of of
avalanche one of one of the the larger
blockchains as well now and at the time
he was working a lot on on bitcoin and
other similar Pro uh projects and he had
research assistants in there working on
it so I was kind of prived all of that I
was excited by it I was close to while
he was doing it I was investing all of
those things and so when I joined meta I
was like kind of the crypto guy sounds
funny now and so my manager at that time
now fast forward back to when he was on
the different team he started messaging
me about crypto stuff and about web 3
because he knew that I had interests
there and so him and I were just talking
a little bit on messenger outside of a
professional context and we were
brainstorming ideas and eventually it
got to a point where we've we built
something for fun just the two of us
outside of work and we launched it and
it got a you know 10,000 users or so in
relatively quick order and then we found
ourselves in a position where he was
ready he was ready to do startups he
always wanted to I never thought that
was going to be something that I was
going to do and I saw my path to
promotion I was like why would I ever
leave this this place is great I'm going
to stay here until I'm a VP and just
like retire into the sunset But
ultimately there was this opportunity
where I had the person who I respected
more than anybody in the world
professionally and we could go leave and
try to do something and we had something
that that had some traction I initially
said like I'm not going to leave until
uh we get funding ultimately I don't
know it was just it was too fun and too
big of an opportunity to give up and so
I left I left all the equity I left all
the opportunities and all of these
things uh in order to start a startup
and there were certainly regrets
throughout the last it's now been over
two years I think it's going to be 3
years in March sheesh but in hindsight
now I don't regret it for a moment so
what is the thing that made you want to
leave because you had this this golden
ticket to probably seven figure plus
earnings yeah even thinking back to it
in hindsight it was kind of crazy um but
there was no convincing from my manager
and now co-founder at that time he was
super respectful of kind of my needs and
my decision and all that ultimately it
was that the things that we were talking
about after hours the things that we
were tinkering with after hours ended up
becoming more fun than my day-to-day job
and ultimately I would wake up in the
morning and I would I would go to meta
work from you know my 7 to 5 7 to 4
whatever it was and I would be thinking
about when work ended being able to
think about those different problems and
so it got to a point where I would have
rather been doing that and I wanted to
spend my time doing that and so without
funding without any of these things just
a little bit of traction who took the
lead you left and then you went and you
said you worked on startups for for two
years now what what's the high level
road map so far yeah so the really high
Lev tldr is that we left with this web3
company we don't need to get into too
much detail at a high level it was like
we called it a social intelligence layer
so combining activities that people were
doing in quotee unquote web 2 largely on
Twitter where people interact with
crypto nfts Etc with what was happening
on chain and then being able to do like
some rankings and predictions and
whatnot based on those combined
movements that was the the first company
and it went well enough like it it grew
significantly got to I guess
significantly in quote it's 100,000
users which is like a significant
portion of the active space at that time
we raised money we were growing great
things and then there was a lot of
interest in acquisition and we
entertained that interest in acquisition
unfortunately for us it ended up being
about the time when the market took a
downturn ironically now here we are
having this conversation and Bitcoin and
crypto is back up to the moon but there
was kind of a lull there right and so we
ended up we ended up selling selling
that company and then we found ourselves
in this awkward position where it's like
we left our jobs for this like big web 3
Vision thing that's not working out what
do we do now we we have each other I had
my questions of like should I just go
back to Big Tech I think that was never
really in the cards for him he was ready
to continue to move on and I figured
whatever like here we are two people I
trust him I trust us we have some money
from the sale let's let's shoot and so
we ended up in this period of just
trying so many different things and this
was probably like a six eight month
period of just like trying ideas and
these were ideas from like truck
factoring and invoicing uh to things in
the design space to things literally all
over the map and nothing was totally
clicking and then throughout that
Journey we built another product which
was pretty fun it allowed you to go to
any website you click one button to copy
that website and directly paste it
contrl V into figma and you would have
fully editable figma frames that you can
move around and edit and what not so a
great tool for designers to able to do
that and this was cool there's a lot of
technical sophistication to it we had to
reverse engineer and and my co-founder
to his credit did did the majority of
this reverse engineering the ability to
paste things in in the first place CU
that was encrypt encrypted and so that
was hugely valuable and there were other
companies in the space that wanted that
technology and so after only a couple of
months they came knocking on the door
and then they ended up buying that
technology call it two Acquisitions hand
wavy a little bit loose and then we find
ourselves in that same position again
okay we have a little bit more money now
in each other but no ideas and we tried
a bunch of more things and ultimately
what we wanted to do was like let's just
do something that a we know really
really well and B that we're passionate
about and ultimately what that was was
interviewing and hiring and helping
candidates prepare for interviews and so
this is like now the beginning of kind
of chat DPT wave and so we're like can
we make AI mock interviews like why
people have to practice with a human why
can't they just practice with an AI
let's make this good and so we tried and
it wasn't very good um some people paid
for it but not many and so we started to
do inperson mock interviews in order to
get training data and we would do these
for free with our paying users in order
to get training data and after every
single one of them they would look at us
and they would be like please let me pay
you to do more of that like that was
huge for me and we would say no no no
we're not an inperson mock interview
business that's crazy like we're we're
technologists we're building cool AI
mock interviews whatever and then
eventually after the the two dozenth
person has asked that you learn as a
startup founder that you have to do what
people are willing to pay for and so we
put on the side of the website in small
inperson mock interviews and big was AI
interviews and then quickly it was just
Stephan and I that that's my co-founders
name it was just Stephan and I and we
were booked like three four five soon
six seven mocks a day um and we were
like oh smokes people people want this
and people want to pay for this and so
that continued to grow tldr hello
interview is the current company uh we
do in-person mock interviews with
current senior engineers and managers
from your target company as well as now
we've brought back some of the AI guided
learning stuff in a much improved
capacity that people are really enjoying
as well as a lot of free and paid
resources you know from an educational
perspective content so when you look
back on
yourent startups or your current lag in
startups from a financial perspective do
you did you out earn what you would have
earned in big Tech because that no okay
not yet anyway I mean there's there's
there's time still yet right but right
right not yet but but what I will say
and this might have been your next
question but I'll beat you to the punch
it's been far worth it the value in
terms of the monetary compensation has
not equated yet certainly not um but the
value in terms of experiences and purely
technical knowledge has far outpace that
of what I would have learned at meta and
so when I think about my projected
earnings over the lifetime of my career
I think that my projected earnings will
be significantly higher than if I had
even stayed and gone to 78 Etc and the
reason for this is that now I've learned
a ton of things that I otherwise
wouldn't have known I've learned how to
learn and I've learned all sorts of
these skills outside of Technology about
how to build a company and these things
are invaluable it hasn't gotten there
yet it's all a ways to go until it gets
there but I'm optimistic that kind of
the compensation will catch up to the
value of increased learning when you
mentioned the stuff that you don't learn
in big Tech that you only learn in
startups that are going to pay dividends
can you talk a little bit about that
yeah totally this is this is one that
I'm I'm pretty passionate about so this
is at least true in my experience this
doesn't extrapolate to everybody of
course but like in starting startups I
realized that I was an idiot like I left
big Tech with a relative ego all these
past promotions I'm the man I'm good I'm
good on my team my team's grown 16
people leading all these cool things
whatever and I leave all of that to
realize I don't know a damn thing at
meta you work on the narrowest not only
had I really coded significantly in a
year and a half at this point because it
was mostly you know ideation and and and
Leadership at this point but to the
extent that I was coding and I was the
quote unquote quote unquote code machine
it was narrowly on this small thing and
so I work on my small thing and then I
hit go and then within six hours that is
affecting three billion people and every
single post that comes into Facebook
right but I didn't figure out how to
make that happened I figured out how to
do my little thing but everyone else did
everything else around me and so like I
had never set up a simple caching layer
i' never configured my own database I
had never stood up my own I suppose I
had done some of these things at a small
capacity in college but by and large and
now I have to do it we have to do it
right stepan and I and so at first like
it was super humbling it was like crap
this is really hard I don't know any of
this and like we're doing a lot of front
end stuff I'd never written a line of
frontend code and I have to learn all of
a sudden at the time like we were
slinging raw jQuery we've now evolved in
a you know using react but like I didn't
know any of these things and it was
incredibly stressful incredibly
overwhelming and now here I am on the
other side of it and I feel like I now
have practical skills you can drop me
into any situation and I can figure it
out I can go to any other big tech
company I can go to any other startup I
can do whatever else and like I have the
experiences that are transferable to our
point about the ic8 at meta not being
particularly transferable I think that's
exactly the point here I've heard very
similar opinion from most people that go
to startups I've only heard one person
that told me that they felt like the
technical learning was not as fast at a
startup because they felt like the
problems that they were dealing with
were smaller trivial you know like just
setting things up you know going through
tutorials getting the database up that's
a solved problem that at meta which in
it's a good thing that it's a solved
problem because the fun and the deeply
technical stuff is when you kind of are
digging into the specialist problems
that are on the the higher level I think
probably the right thing is to do it in
the inverse order than I did it oh so
start at a startup and then go into big
Tech I wouldn't recommend that for
someone from a career perspective but I
would recommend it from a learning
perspective because then you get the
bread you understand how to do all of
these things and then the optimizations
that you're doing in big Tech are within
context and I think that that's that
would be valuable I think yeah to
generalize it I think big Tech Absol
absolutely gets you the depth and
startups absolutely gets you the bread
you got to do everything even outside
the technical you got to do all this
random stuff that you might not and and
and maybe the last point there is that
what I wish I had done while I was at
meta has been a bit more inquisitive
about how things worked and so it was
easy to focus on my day job and the
reality is like you only have so much
time in the day so I don't know if I
would have been able to pull this off
but like to Facebook's cashing layer to
those who who aren't familiar like I
used it every day as an abstraction
right I I I called into it every single
day by many layers of abstraction but
didn't care to or know significantly
about how it actually worked that's not
what I worked on and it didn't matter to
me in hindsight maybe even out of hours
I wish I had been a bit more inquisitive
there like Facebook publishes all of
these different blogs and now that I do
so much time you know Learning System
design both to teach it for our YouTube
channel for the content that we write I
read all these blogs now and I wish I
had done some of that while I was
actually at meta yeah I mean curiosity
is probably the biggest tool for
actually driving learning technical
learning so totally agree with that and
so for someone who's let's say someone's
a big Tech engineer in at a yeah one of
these big companies and they're thinking
about one day they'd like to try a
startup but they you know are kind of
thinking what do they need to see to
actually think that okay now is the time
and now it's a good time to go to a
startup what advice would you have for
them this is super hard I actually wrote
I wrote a post two years ago or so and I
posted it on blind and they got like a
decent amount of attention and it was be
basically convincing big Tech employees
that like they should leave and and
start a startup or join a startup and it
was through the lens and i' had good
intentions from what you and I are
discussing now like you're going to
learn more here was my experience now
rightfully so I got ripped to shreds in
the comments of the post blind is an
aggressive place first of all but it was
because you know I I I struck a nerve
with many people and I was insensitive
to the fortunate situation that I had
which is that I was financially secure
and I didn't have a family that I was
supporting and like I could afford to
take this risk and not get paid for a
while and it was going to be okay so I
recognize most people aren't in that
situation and so the reality is only you
know what makes sense for you
financially if you're purely optimizing
for your own learning your own technical
learning and your own improvements from
a technical perspective and I think
Beyond a technical perspective then I
would do it as soon as you can if you're
brand new to your career I'd probably
wait until you're at least a senior
engineer like go go up the ranks of big
Tech if you're if you're new to it and
then consider making the switch I
wouldn't do it before that but you're
going to learn a significant degree more
somewhere else is what I think you're
going to learn a lot about how
organizations work at Big Tech that's
important you're going to learn a lot
about people's skills and you will of
course learn things technically but
you'll learn more somewhere else and
maybe the middle ground is to like go to
a a series b or series C or something
ASAP spend your time there and then
consider starting your own thing if you
can afford to financially of course it
is a privilege to be to not have a
family to be financially secure enough
to to be able to do it so yeah that that
that makes sense and I think like I said
almost all of my friends at this point
have gone off and done startups so um I
think what you're saying makes sense and
a lot of people do enjoy it and and it
is like this fun thing to do and and now
now is a cool time to do a startup with
you know the the advancements of of llms
not just in terms of making a generic AI
this company but in terms of like
accelerating your own rate of progress
hello interview is still to this day
just Stephan and I in terms of two
full-time employees and we've slung a
lot of code and a lot of that code has
been accelerated based on the tools that
we have at our disposal now and so like
what would have been many weak Cycles at
even a meta with a team of some number
of Engineers if you have two highly
capable engineers and Claude at your
disposal you can move pretty quick and
plenty of opinions about where Cloud's
useful where it slows you down whatever
but I'll I'll hold that for a different
conversation I think that could be
really interesting so for the last part
of this interview and I think this is my
favorite part always is just reflecting
looking back on everything your career
going into meta growing so quickly and
then going into startups and you know
through those Acquisitions and
everything I'm curious to look at all of
that and ask you some questions and so
the first one that I'm curious about is
and maybe this is similar to what we
were just talking about but what periods
of your career did you feel like you had
the most skill growth the skill growth
was certainly as we just alluded to the
startup stuff undoubtedly of course
there's a lot of skill growth in the
early early days of your career as well
but everything pales in comparison to
the to the startup trainy from skill
growth once you left to to do the
startup that was like the you never felt
growth that that uh fast yeah totally
and it's all the things that they say
growth should be it was uncomfortable
certainly at first it was stressful it
was like emotional at times credit to to
my co-founder for putting up with some
you know emotional moments for me where
where things felt difficult but yeah
here we are on the other side of it and
it was all tremendously worth it I'm
curious about because your career's
grown so quickly when you think about
how many hours a week that you were
working throughout the different parts
of your career yeah how much were you
working during meta I usually tell
people not a lot and that's generally my
advice but like in a reflection it's
it's probably not totally honest I loved
what I was doing and so I got to work at
8:00 or so maybe 8:30 and I left work at
5:30 or 6 but I got home and I
decompressed and I sat down I watched TV
I did whatever and like I would open up
my laptop and I would check an
experiment or I would tweak something or
I would do something because I was like
passionate and excited about it to the
point where sometimes I would wake up in
the middle of the night because much of
what we were doing was training models
which training takes time I would wake
up in the middle of the night being like
did did my Run finish like let me go let
me go check it CU I was just excited and
so if you actually accounted for all of
those hours certainly it's more than
your average 40 hours a week but at at
the same time and this part's important
I love the snowboard Wednesdays I would
leave work at like 2:00 and go drive up
to the mountains being in Seattle they
were only an hour and a half two hours
away and I would I was no word until
8:00 p.m. and then drive home um so like
you can do both and you weren't working
weekends or anything sounds like you
were okay no if I if it was something I
was passionate about but not really
right right right okay so this sounds
like I don't know maybe 50 hours a week
or something um one of the more balanced
uh career paths what about when you did
startups though ex exactly EV it changed
okay so so particularly with that first
company when I was both struggling to
learn and consume everything I needed to
I didn't have my feet under me yet and
it was a company that like it was doing
a lot of face fast-paced realtime data
analytics and so like a lot of things
can break and when they do break because
it's money people really care about it
and it was stressful and so I was
working all the time like I'd be waking
up at 7 or 8: and I would stop working
at midnight or 2:00 a.m. in many cases
and like I couldn't leave my house
without my laptop like I distinctly
remember one instance where I felt like
things were pretty good I was going to
leave and go to a friend's birthday
party that was just up the street from
me and I went and I brought my laptop
and I sat down and I ordered my food and
then binging my pager Duty starts going
off at the whole sight sound ah and I'm
like God and I grab my laptop and I
start running down the hill to try to
because this was one particular moment
where I think my co-founder was either
on vacation or at something with his
kids or you know like I was the the only
one to do it and so that was stressful
and then now we've sort of come full
circle and that hello interview is
starting to become much more stable
things don't necessarily break it's
fortunately in the nature of the
business not something where people are
like eagerly staring at the site every
second there's less opportunities for
things to go wrong and now my hours are
still more than my metad days just
because you're passionate about your own
company and you want to make it
successful but I go to friend's
birthdays without my laptop okay okay
that's good
I remember you you telling me that you
looking and you also wrote a post about
it the work life balance and you know
not but by you doing startups you're
you're kind of contradicting that by
working such an insane amount of hours
so uh what do you say to that yeah so I
was at this point I think you and I
chatted about this a little bit I was at
this point at the end of my meta career
where I had kind of come to like this
come to Jesus moment where I had been
chasing the next ring in the ladder the
whole time I had just been focused on
that that was about to come to an end
certainly if I got that seven promotion
I need to kind of figure out what else
matters in life I've been hyper
optimizing for my career growth and like
letting other things around Me Maybe
slip
consequentially um and I had convinced
myself of this realization that like
there's two paths in life one you make
sure you're really passionate about work
and you spend all your hours on that
because that's what you love and it
checks all of your boxes it checks your
relationship boxes it checks your
fulfillment boxes obviously the monetary
boxes or you just look at work as
something that supports your passions
financially and so you go to work you do
a good job you do a great job from 9: to
5 and then you hang out with your
friends and you travel the world and you
live a great fulfilled life finding
other things to find you passion and so
I was excited to go for option b and I
thought that's what I was transitioning
to after hopefully a seven promotion and
yeah here I am so be it things went in a
different direction I think that I might
be able to pull back out option b in a
handful of years down the line at least
I'm still in option A where I'm
passionate and excited about what I do
and helping people and you know that's
fantastic you mentioned earlier I think
uh a while ago when you're talking about
starting a startup you talked a little
bit about regrets is there anything when
you look back on your career what's the
biggest regret that you have something
that others could learn from potentially
yeah I think that I think that my
biggest regret would be not slowing down
and like I I took shortcuts and I I
still have a tendency to do this
sometimes now although I push myself to
be much better here for what it's worth
but like you need to understand how
things work and so there are certain
approaches that you can take in order to
accomplish the task through iteration
and you'll get there but once it works
you might move on alternatively you get
there and then you're inquisitive about
why it actually worked and I think that
this is just a much more sustainable
foundation and so like at meta it was
easy to kind of experiment see numbers
go up I was in a very quantitative kind
of field or team where we had metrics
and those metrics would go up or they
would not go up and if they went up
success and you generally have an idea
for why but I wasn't as inquisitive as I
could have been about what like the
actual underlying particularly technical
cause and then the same was true in the
early days of startups because I didn't
feel like I had the time I was learning
so much and I was trying to just get my
feet under me and I was trying to move
that like once I got it to work it was
like okay that works now like next thing
and then now only within the last year I
feel like I've been able to make that
transition kind of recognize that as an
issue and I have more time now now I'm
back to that like I can do you know my
work in 70% of the time and I have a 30%
of my time to dedicate to something else
and now that it's not about career
growth that 30% can go to actually
learning and understanding and so this
is a combination of like reading the
engineering blogs from other companies
that are coming out me being inquisitive
about underlying kind of like libraries
or platforms that we're using how they
work why they work how they were built
and I think this is a a valid and
important shift in in the way that I
think about technology got it so taking
the time to rather than just pure impact
machine launch something onto the next
thing launch something on the next thing
you wish that you took the time to
deeply understand things after things
are launched too just for the sake of
your own technical growth which has
long-term benefits exactly and I think
that for all of the great things about
meta that that you and I have talked
about now that was probably the negative
culturally is that it encouraged this
culture of just like ship it and run and
keep going impact impact impact impact
and so I didn't need to ask those
questions of like how does ta actually
work this thing that I use every day
right because it didn't matter to me but
in terms of my growth as an engineer it
would have been fantastic if I
understood that and it would have been
fantastic if I could then ask the
engineers who were working on it
questions as they were coming up that's
something that that I regret on doing
yeah the cultural I guess the other
thing is move fast and break things so
yeah yeah that's also kind of I was good
at that yeah breaking things too but I
can usually fix them fast enough that
nobody notice or cared but yeah right
right right right yeah I've had my fish
sh breakages too okay and then the last
thing that I like to ask everyone is if
you could go back to Evan who's just
graduating college and is entering the
industry and you were to tell that Evan
something what would be the advice that
you give yourself just starting out in
your career yeah I'm going to I'm going
to take a more maybe emotional angle on
this as opposed to technical or career
or answerid but like I think the advice
to me would be to really invest in
relationships and the aspects outside of
work like I'm only just now realizing in
the last year and a half or so that like
I was underinvested in in friendships
and romantic relationships and things of
this nature and it was largely because I
was putting so much effort into work
even if it wasn't an hours wise like
that's where my optimizations were and
you realize that like you spend all this
time Road mapping goaling checking in
with yourself about your career
progression but in terms of like General
Life progression I didn't apply nearly
that same Vigor and so I think that that
had a negative consequence and only
moving to La now years ago did the shift
and this is because I got pulled out of
the tech bubble now a lot of my friends
don't work in Tech and we invest a lot
more in each other both financially and
from a Time perspective and I have found
that my life is so much more fulfilled
because of this and so work continues to
be a focus it continues to grow things
are great there but now like I have all
these people that I can rely on and like
I'm moving apartments right now and and
I have any number of people that I can
call to help me move and these small
things are like you know like I said
it's a bit sentimental but they're
they're really what matter in life U
more so than your quick career
progression so I wish I had learned to
more fairly allocate time between those
two and effort so if you could go back
and grow slower yet retain more
relationships and have done more outside
of work would you make that change
Looking Back Now that you know how
things went if I was given that binary
choice I think I would but I don't think
that would have been the choice I had
more than enough time I just didn't do
it uh it just like it wasn't something
that I was investing enough in and I
just like didn't understand the
importance of it until I got a little
bit older and wiser in age so to anybody
else I think you can absolutely do both
hindsight if I had to make the binary
decision of course your relationships
matter more than anything else in the
world so I would optimize for those as I
as opposed to Career makes sense okay
well that's all the questions that I had
Evan I really enjoyed this conversation
I loved how it had some back and forth
and we could kind of both go over our
our fast progressions to meta and show
show everyone you know what they might
be able to learn from that and so with
that being said um you know this is
opportunity to plug anything you'd like
to do you want to shout out anything
yeah totally well first off likewise
this was a super super fun conversation
I can't actually believe looking at the
time L quickly it we moved through it
because you I was certainly having a lot
of fun chatting with you um in terms of
plugs yeah absolutely hello
interview.com that's the current startup
that's the current company if you are
preparing for software engineering
interviews you should absolutely check
us out we have everything from if you
want just free resources to learn and of
course I'm biased but we've heard over
and over again from the community that
these are some of the best free
resources that exist on the internet to
if you want kind of self-guided practice
we've got you covered there and then all
the way of course to the mock interviews
and we go through extreme lengths to
make sure that we only hire the absolute
best coaches we make sure that if
anybody drops below kind of our bar of
expectations from a coach that that we
part ways and we move on to to another
coach that that can perform at the level
required for our candidates to succeed
and so so we hear a lot of great
feedback check it out would love to be
able to help you prepare for your
interviews as well and maybe the last
thing there since I'm assuming you're
viewing this on YouTube you can also uh
YouTube search for Hello interview we
have a YouTube channel it's largely me
talking about interviews and breaking
down common system design problems so
you can see how I think through these
problems give that a watch too
everything on there of course is is
completely free yeah and I'll be putting
links to everything in the in the
description the show notes so you can
take a look at that and yeah the last
thing i' would add by the way about
hello interview just to give you some
unbiased feedback I can tell you a story
that one of my roommates was recently
interviewing and he didn't know that
I've been talking to Evan and anything
he's just been talking to me unbiasedly
about mock interview services and what
the resources are in terms of system
design and he tried to interview IO and
it was okay and then he didn't have
super great results in his one of his
first rounds so he had to re-evaluate
everything and then he found hello
interview and he remember specifically
he credited the free resources he said
that was really helpful for him to learn
because he had read some other book on
system design was not super helpful also
he was overconfident when it came to
system design because he felt like Oh
I'm a senior engineer and I've been
designing systems at work but actually
the interview process is this contrived
thing that you need to study
specifically and hello interviews free
resources as well as doing mocks
themselves were the critical thing that
actually like helped my my roommate a
lot so although I haven't used the the
interview service I would say this is
like a very strong recommendation that I
could personally recommend because
someone I trust uh had such a good
review with it yeah recommend you take a
look at hello interview hello your
friend that's awesome yeah appreciate
that cool all right well thanks so much
Evan yeah that's that's all we got